DAVID MCBEE

Bakersfield, CA 93309

Phone: 7602209498 | Email: davidmcbee8@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/david-mcbee-pmp | Github: https://github.com/davidmcbee

Portfolio: https://davidmcbee.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Seasoned Data Analyst with business intelligence, enterprise and solution architecture experience across multiple clients, projects and industries. Collaborative and effective communicator and technical manager. Military background with security clearance. Enjoy wrangling, cleaning, analyzing and visualizing data to tell its story.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools / Languages: VS Code, Jupyter Notebooks, GitHub, Tableau, PowerBI, SAP BI, Python, Matplotlib, SciPi, Pandas, NumPy, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Flask, D3, Plotly, R, VBA, SQL, Business Objects, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Excel.

Skills: Statistical testing/analysis, Google Maps, API/ ETL, Graphs/Visualizations, Web scraping, Supervised, Unsupervised Machine Learning, Deep Neural Networks, Logistics Regression, Random Forest, Balanced Random Forest Classification/Prediction, AdaBoost, K-means, Hierarchical clustering, ARIMA, LSTM, Scaling, Elbow curves, Dimensionality reduction, Principal Component Analysis (PCA), Dendrograms, AWS

PROJECTS

DATA ANALYTICS PROGRAM - All projects available here | https://davidmcbee.github.io/Portfolio/

- Avocado Price Forecasting | https://github.com/davidmcbee/Health and Avocados
 Created time series forecasting machine learning models.

 Tools / Languages used: Python, ARIMA, LSTM multivariate time series model with lags.
- Neural Network Charity Analysis | <u>https://github.com/davidmcbee/Neural Network Charity Analysis.git</u> Analyzed a charity funding organization for effectiveness of donations. Tools / Languages used: Python, Numpy Tensor Flow, Sklearn
- World Weather Travel Tool |

https://github.com/davidmcbee/World_Weather_Analysis_Challenge

Created a trip planning weather guide using Google Maps. Tools / Languages used: Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst/Enterprise Architect Sentinel Peak Resources

2019 – 2020

Bakersfield, CA

Helped manage change for small startup oil and gas company by creating current and target state data maps, architecture products and led successful acquisition of over \$2M in Analysis tools and enterprise HR and content management applications. Supported architecture of MS SQL based data warehouse and Master Data Management (MDM) implementation.

Upgrade operational Engineering Data

- Reconciled business and engineering data across 6 business systems and 8 MS SQL servers (50 + databases) resulting in new Key Performance Indicators (KPIs), increased system performance, response time, improved data quality and transparency.
- Tools/languages used T-SQL, MS SQL Server, SSMS, SSIS, Power BI

ACQUISITION EVALUATION PROJECTS

 Managed RFP effort and evaluation for time series data analysis capability, content management system, HR onboarding system and safety management system. Understanding and analysis of technology and architecture roadmap provided most cost-effective solutions

Senior Technology Consultant Accenture

2006 – 2018

San Diego, CA

Primary responsibilities included client management, project management, data and business process analysis. Led projects and operations across 7 clients and 6 industries. Implemented business intelligence solutions, visualizations, analytic databases and meaningful answers based on analysis. Managed operations for level 3 enterprise data help desk. Experience includes project planning, acquiring/managing human resources. Managed budget, status reporting and issue resolution.

OPERATIONS ANALYSIS IMPLEMENTATION

 Led analytics and visualization development to produce Microsoft SQL analytics tool, reports and dashboards to evaluate incident resolution to SLAs. Solution provided insight into reasons for delays that led to significant improvement to incident resolution throughput.

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE SOLUTION ARCHITECT

- Due to track record of success was specifically brought on to work with difficult client. Significantly
 contributed to saving \$10 million-dollar per year client by effectively transforming financial
 reporting operations.
- Worked hand in hand with client counterpart to create digital roadmap synchronizing client priorities, budget and SAP's roadmap. Planned ECC, BI, HANA, reporting and analytics architecture capabilities. Planning effort resulted in 5-year execution strategy.

SAP BI AND BUSINESS OBJECTS (BO) INTEGRATION

- Led internal and external teams in full life cycle implementation to integrate large external enterprise system reporting capability into BI data warehouse for internal merger (\$7M across two years).
- Brought project in on budget and on time while developing team. Produced 123 WEBI's, Crystal reports, dashboards and Analysis for OLAP products.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certificate: U.C, Berkeley

2020 – 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

Master of Business Administration (MBA): Columbia College

Master of Science in Operations Research: Naval Postgraduate School

AWS Solution Architect - Associate: Certification

Project Management Professional (PMP)

SCRUM Agile Master Certified

OTHER

Military: U.S. Naval Officer - Secret Clearance

Started veteran hire mentorship program, taught IT foundation class for transitioning military